Guide to the Margaret Spak-Hoy papers, 1966-1978
Spak-Hoy, Margaret papers, 1966-1978
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Margaret Spak-Hoy papers, 1966-1978.
4051
Margaret Spak-Hoy, 1946-
4.1 cubic ft.
Drafts, notes, course outlines, exams, article, reports, newsletters, magazines, pamphlets.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Draft of thesis; notes; course outline, exams, and lecture notes; and articles, reports, newsletters, magazines, and pamphlets related to medical care, birth control, family planning, and health care. Includes materials from Cornell University Department of University Health Services; American College Health Association; and Tompkins County Health Alliance.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
After graduating from Cornell University (M.P.S.) in 1976, Spak-Hoy taught a Medical Care course at Ithaca College.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Draft of thesis; notes; course outline, exams, and lecture notes; and articles, reports, newsletters, magazines, and pamphlets related to medical care, birth control, family planning, and health care. Includes materials from Cornell University Department of University Health Services; American College Health Association; and Tompkins County Health Alliance.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Spak-Hoy, Margaret, 1946-; American College Health Association.; Cornell University. Dept. of University Health Services.; Tompkins County Health Alliance (N.Y.)
Subjects:
Birth control.; Health maintenance organizations.; Health planning--New York (State)--Tompkins County.; Medical care--New York (State)--Tompkins County.; College teachers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Network, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Consulting project for East Oragne General Hospital with Network - includes methodology and proposal
- Medical Care Organizations Articles, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  History of health care systems, various articles
- Death/Dying (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Treating patients humanly, terminally ill patients - articles, excerpt from book Sickness and Society
- HMO Paper, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Unpublished paper concerning HMO's and industralization of health care
- HMO Paper (Drafts), 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- HMO Paper (Notes and Drafts), 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Fiscal Crisis, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Collection of articles on fiscal crisis in U.S.
- Health Maintenance of Organizations (Articles), 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Health Maintenance Organizations (Articles and Notes), 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Marie Beaune, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Unpublished draft of thesis - Women as Commodities under Late Capitalism
- Ehrenrichs, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Organizing health workers - articles
- Health Law (Newsletters), 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Birth Control Handbook (Rough drafts), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Ithaca Socialist Feminist Collection, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Principles of unity, articles, minutes
- Quantitative Methods for Evaluating Health Care Services, 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Articles and reports
- Hospital Workers (Articles) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- International Health Care Services, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Articles on China, Britain, Australia, Canada
- Maintaining Health, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Articles concerning holistic health
- Menstrual Paper (Notes and Survey), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Tompkins County Citizens for Better Health Care (Questionnaires), 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Health Rights (Newsletters), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Educational Materials for Establishing a Birth Control Clinic (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Booklets, brochures, bulletins
- Lempert Project, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Outline - bibliography for project on teenage sexual behavior
- Socialist Perspectives on Health Care (Articles), 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Ithaca Socialist Feminist Collection, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Minutes and study group questions
- Nurse Midwifery (Articles), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Health Care System (Articles), 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Health Care Delivery (Articles), 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Birth Control Handbooks, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Contraception and VD (Articles and Reports), 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Contraception and VD (Articles and Reports), 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Health and Social Services, 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Outline, notes, articles
- Abortion, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Reports, articles, clippings, reprints
- Abortion (Reprints) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Health Movement Organization (Papers), 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Family Planning Digest (Newsletter), 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Family Planning Digest, monthly extract (Newsletter), 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Family Planning Perspectives (Magazine), 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Family Planning Perspectives (Magazine), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Family Planning Perspectives (Magazine), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Family Planning Perspectives (Magazine), 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Health Law Course Materials, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Course outline, assignments, take-home exam, notes
- Health Law Course Materials, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Health Law Course Materials (Court Cases), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Health Law Course Materials (Court Cases), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Publications, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Publications, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Radical Publications, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Health Perspectives (Newsletter), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Health Status of the Population (Reports and Reprints), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Materialist Epidemology, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Notes developed at Health Marxist Organization meetings
- Materialist Epidemology, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Affirmative Action Struggle in B & PA, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Minutes, letters, articles
- Health Planning (Articles, brochures), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Health Planning (Articles, brochures), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- International Health (Pamphlets), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Bylaws - Board for the Tompkins Co. Family Medicine Program (Drafts), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Planned Parenthood of Tompkins County, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Annual report, notes, correspondence
- Medical Care Course, Ithaca College, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Course outlines, exams, lecture notes
- Medical Care Course, Ithaca College, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Exams, lecture notes
- Medical Care Course, Ithaca College, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- World Fertility Patterns (Chart), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)